Zachary Andrews

B.S. in Computer Science 2424 W 40th St, Apt 35, Kansas City, KS 66103 zackandrews29@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/zachary-andrews-b27039198

SUMMARY

Result focused Computer Science graduate with data engineering and research experience. Ability to work independently and as part of a team to define and analyze requirements, determine multiple solutions with pros/cons, and implement and innovate to finalize the best possible outcome. Passion for transportation, learning, and helping others. Areas of expertise include:

• 3+ years in school: C/C++, React, CSS, HTML, PHP, JavaScript

1 year: Cloud Computing, AWS1 year: Linux and SQL scripting

• 1+ years: Python, Git

EDUCATION

The University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS - B.S. in Computer Science

August 2019-Fall 2023

GPA: 3.25

Last Semester GPA: 3.82

Coursework in: Cybersecurity, Networks (TCP/IP, Wireshark, OSI Model), Programming (Object-oriented design, data structures, and best industry practices)

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Capital One

August 2021-September 2022

Data Engineer

Plano, TX (remote)

- Utilized an in-house machine learning algorithm to automate validation of new datasets and display results with a REST API, driving business goals by automating tedious manual dataset validation
- Worked on meticulous documentation in YAML and unit testing in Python for the new API, testing output and clarifying to users how API should be used
- Created Tableau dashboards and Snowflake tables conveniently displaying metrics related to data governance
- Improved knowledge of metric sources to prepare for data migration, identifying true sources where available to help provide programmatic access to datasets that produced metrics
- Various Python, SQL, and ETL automation scripting projects
- Experience in Agile principles and Scrum framework with Jira

Slusky Computational Biology Lab January 2021-July 2021

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Lawrence, KS

- Built programs in Python involving generation of pseudorandom sequences, one-hot encoding, and plot generation
- Began to train a neural network to identify a specific kind of protein
- Developed a good foundation in Python

PROJECTS

- KU Hackathon project (ELI_), frontend in React and CSS, backend MongoDB: https://github.com/tuckspaint/HACKKU23.git
- Hands-on experience working with team members programming a virtual game of chess via HTML, CSS and JavaScript; created some UI features and the algorithms for check and checkmate: https://github.com/EuslidEuclid97/eecs448-project4-ChessGame.git
- Personal website in progress (<u>zackandrewsdev.com</u>) implementing CI/CD with GitHub Actions and hosted with Nginx proxy on EC2 server; built with TypeScript and React (https://github.com/EuslidEuclid97/professionalWebsite)

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Credly

LEADERSHIP AND HONORS

University Honors Program, Honor Roll 2019-2020, Engineering Honor Roll Fall 2023 Leadership at Sunrise Movement KU, Environs KU (environmentalist clubs)